The Minitab Customization Tool is a Graphical User interface that helps you to create a configuration file to modify your Minitab 16 installation when you deploy. Use the instructions below to create a custom installation.

Note: Type setup.exe /help at the Command Prompt to access Setup Help at any time.

1  Copy the installation files to a network location.

2  Open the Command Prompt and navigate to the Minitab 16 setup files.

3  Type Setup.exe /admin to access the Minitab 16 Customization Tool.

4  Set the options for deployment.

5  Click Save Configuration to save the configuration file to a network location. You must save the config.xml file next to the Setup.exe and other installation files or specify a config.xml file on the command line using the syntax /config "path" (for example, setup.exe /config "\\ServerName\PathTo\config.xml").

Note: If you did not copy the installation files to a network location in step 1, you can check Copy Installation Files to save both the installation files and the configuration file to the same network location.

6  Click Save.

7  Use the deployment method of your choice to deploy Minitab 16:
   a  If you use SMS, Altiris, Tivoli or any other Enterprise Management Tool for deployment, use Setup.exe.
   b  If you use Active Directory/Group Policy, read the following important information. There are two methods for deploying via Active Directory/Group Policy:  
      1  Use a Startup Script (Recommended)
         - Create a configuration file using the Minitab 16 Customization Tool.
         - Ensure that the config.xml file is next to the Setup.exe.
         - Call Setup.exe within a Startup Script in Active Directory.
      2  Use Group Policy Software Deployment (assigment only; updates not supported)
         - Create a configuration file using the Minitab 16 Customization Tool.
         - Ensure that the config.xml file is next to the Setup.exe.
         - Assign the Core.msi to the GPO (Group Policy Object). You can find this .msi in the administrative package that you created under the Core folder (Core/Core.msi).

Note: If you silently deploy Minitab through Group Policy, setup.exe continues to run in the background even after the user logs on and until the installation is complete.

If you use Organizational Defaults to set the default Minitab user profile, you must save the orgdefs.reg file next to the language pack MSI for each language you install. For more information on Organizational Defaults and its applications, please see the Minitab 16 Installation Guide.